Guide to the Open Media Records TAM.197
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Open Media Records
1989-2009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Open Media (Westfield, N.J.)
Ruggiero, Greg.
Sahulka, Stuart
TAM.197
2.5 Linear Feet in two record cartons and 1 manuscript box
Open Media (Westfield N.J.), a radical publishing company, was founded in 1991 by Gregg Ruggiero and Stuart Sahulka in opposition to the Persian Gulf War, and continues to publish in pamphlet form (initially as the Open magazine pamphlet series, later as the Open Media pamphlet series), and as books, notably anthologies, a wide array of scholars, activists and artists committed to a common vision of social justice, democracy and human rights for all. The collection contains correspondence with authors, including Noam Chomsky andother notables, bookstores, publishers; typescripts and other materials documenting the editorial and publishing process, publicity materials, and financial records.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Gregg Ruggiero and Stuart Sahulka on behalf of Open Media in 1994; additional materials were found in the repository in 2018. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1994.019, 2018.009, and 2018.034.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Historical Note
Open Media (Westfield N.J.), a radical publishing company, was founded in 1991 by Gregg Ruggiero and Stuart Sahulka in opposition to the Persian Gulf War, and continues to publish in pamphlet form (initially as the Open magazine pamphlet series, later as the Open Media pamphlet series), and as books, notably anthologies, a wide array of scholars, activists and artists committed to a common vision of social justice, democracy and human rights for all. These works are sometimes published in cooperation with other publishers, and some have been translated into other languages.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Open Media Oral Histories (OH 078)
Scope and Contents
The records contain correspondence with authors, bookstores, publishers; typescripts and other materials documenting the editorial and publishing process, publicity materials, authors permission forms, and financial records. Most fully documented are the publishing of Critical Mass (1996), an anthology of writings opposing nuclear energy and weapons, Jailhouse Lawyers (2009), and an unpublished book project titled "The Information Superhighway." The principal correspondents are Open Media co-founders Greg Ruggerio and Stuart Sahulka. Notable correspondents include authors Helen Caldicott, Noam Chomsky, Mike Davis, David Dellinger, Daniel Ellsberg, Andre Gunder Frank, Manning Marable and Marge Piercy.
A set of approximately 150 interview transcripts from the Denver, Colorado based radio program Alternative Radio was added to this collection in 2018. Interviews date from 1991 to 2002 and feature scholars and public intellectuals discussing topics related to the environment, public health, and politics.
Separated Materials
Two audiocassettes were separated to the Library's Oral History collection.
Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Nuclear disarmament.; Social justice.; Antinuclear movement.; Democracy -- United States.; Prisoners -- Civil rights -- United States.; Mass media -- Political aspects -- United States.; Internet -- Political aspects.; Radicals -- United States.; Anti-globalization movement.; Open media pamphlet series; Open magazine pamphlet series; Marable, Manning, 1950-2011 -- Correspondence; Piercy, Marge -- Correspondence; Sahulka, Stuart; Dellinger, David T., 1915-2004 -- Correspondence; Davis, Mike, 1946- -- Correspondence; Caldicott, Helen. -- Correspondence; Chomsky, Noam -- Correspondence; Ruggiero, Greg.; Open Media (Westfield, N.J.); Ruggiero, Greg.; Sahulka, Stuart
- The Ad and the Ego (Documentary, 1996: Original Title "Reality Check"): to include Ruggiero and Sahulka, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alternative Radio: Broadcast Transcripts, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alternative Radio: Broadcast Transcripts, 1991-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- Artfux: Articles, Clippings, and (copies of) Photographs, 1990-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Authors' Permission Letters (Alphabetical), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bookstores (Invoices and Other Documents): A - F, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bookstores (Invoices and Other Documents): G - K, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bookstores (Invoices and Other Documents): L - R, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bookstores (Invoices and Other Documents): S - T, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bookstores (Invoices and Other Documents): U - Z, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Authors: Barsamian, David, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, Authors: Baxandall, Rosalyn, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Authors: Caldicott, Helen, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Authors: Chernovsenko, Vladimir, Oct 1995 - Mar 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Authors: Chomsky, Noam, Apr 1992 - Jan 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, Authors: Davis, Mike, Mar 1992 - Jan 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Authors: Dawkins, Kristen, Aug 1995 - Apr 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Authors: Dellinger, David, Feb 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Authors: Diamond, Sara, Apr 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, Authors: Ellsburg, Daniel, Nov 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Authors: Ewen, Stuart, Dec 1991 - Mar1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, Authors: Frank, Andre Gunder, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, Authors: Frank, Thomas Carr, Aug 1995 - Oct 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, Authors: Kaye, Harvey, Oct 1994 - Dec 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, Authors: LaDuke, Winonia, Sep 1993 - Oct 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, Authors: Marable, Manning, Nov 1991 - Nov 1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, Authors: Martin, Stephan Paul, Feb 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, Authors: McChesney, Robert W., Oct 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, Authors: Piercy, Marge, Nov 1994 - Dec 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, Authors: Scarlett, Jennifer, May 1992 - Nov 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, Authors: Schiller, Herb, Mar 1994 - May 1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, Authors: Unknown, 1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, Authors: Zinn, Howard, Mar 1992 - Mar 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, General (Chronological), 1991 - 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, Publishers: A - Z, 1993 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Agata, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Het Fort Van Sjakoo, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Icaria, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Papieren Tijger, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Les Publications Du Quartier Libre, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Vallecchi Editore, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, Publishers: Whitehall Printing Company, 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Critical Mass (Book): Campaign for Peace and Democracy, Funder: Correspondence and Grant Proposals, Apr 1992 - Apr 1996 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Critical Mass (Book): Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament and European Nuclear Disarmament, Nov 1994 - Dec 1994 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Critical Mass (Book) Correspondence: Authors (Alphabetical), Nov 1994 - Oct 1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Critical Mass (Book) Correspondence, General, 1994-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Critical Mass (Book): Dalai Lama (Correspondence), Nov 1994 - Jul 1995 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Critical Mass (Book): Financial, Nov 1994 - Jul 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Critical Mass (Book): Gensuikin Proposal: Steps to Abolish Nuclear Weapons, Nov 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Critical Mass (Book): Layouts, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Critical Mass (Book): Photographs (Photocopies), undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Critical Mass (Book): Promotional Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Critical Mass (Book): World Uranium Hearing (Salzburg, Austria), Feb 1995 - Apr 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
- "Diary 1991" No. 1, 1991-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
- "Diary 1991" No. 2, 1993-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Distributors: AK Distribution, Sep 1992 - Oct 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Distributors: AK Press, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Distributors: Armadillo Distribution, 1993 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Distributors: Autonome Distribution, 1994-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Distributors: Deboer, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Distributors: Desert Moon Periodicals, 1992-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Distributors: E.G. Smith Distribution, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Distributors: Fine Print Distribution, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Distributors: Fine Print Distribution, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Distributors: Follett College Stores Corporation, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Distributors: Het Fort Sjakoo, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Distributors: Inland Book Company, 1991-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Distributors: Inland Book Company, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Distributors: Left Bank Distribution, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Distributors: Padjav Educational Source, Inc., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Distributors: Small Changes, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Distributors: Unique Books, Inc., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Financial Records: Bank Statements, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Financial Records: Bank Statements, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Financial Records: Falcon Printing, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Financial Records: The New Press, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Frank, Andre Gunder: Unpublished Pamphlet re: Gulf War 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Information Superhighway" Book (Anthology Never Published): Correspondence, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Information Superhighway" Book Contributors: Kranich, Nancy, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- "Information Superhighway" Book Contributors: Schiller, Herbert, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Information Superhighway" Book: Research Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "Information Superhighway" Book: Research Materials, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- "Information Superhighway" Book: Research Materials, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Jailhouse Lawyers: Prisoners Defending Prisoners v. The USA (City Lights Books, 2009): Interview with Greg Ruggiero (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Jailhouse Lawyers: Prisoners Defending Prisoners v. The USA (City Lights Books, 2009): Typscript for Review: Part 1: Chapters 1-12, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Jailhouse Lawyers: Prisoners Defending Prisoners v. The USA (City Lights Books, 2009): Typscript for Review: Part 2: Chapters 4-8, undated (Box 2, Folder 13A)
- Letters Received, May 1989 - May 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Letters Received, Jun 1991 - Dec 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Letters Received, Jan 1992 - Mar 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Letters Received, Apr 1992 - Jun 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Letters Received, Jul 1992 - Dec 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Letters Received, Jan 1993 - Mar 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Letters Received, Apr 1993 - Jul 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Letters Received, Aug 1993 - Sep 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Letters Received, Oct 1993 - Dec 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Letters Received, Jan 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Letters Received, Feb 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Letters Received, Mar 1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Letters Received, Apr 1994 - Jul 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Letters Received, Aug 1994 - Dec 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Letters Received, Jan 1995 - May 1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Letters Received, Jun 1995 - Dec 1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Letters Received, Jan 1996 - Aug 1996 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Libraries (Invoices and Other Documents), 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- New American Crisis (Anthology, 1995): Correspondence with The New Press, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- New American Crisis (Anthology, 1995): Memorandum of Agreement with The New Press, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Open Fire (Anthology, 1993): Memorandum of Agreement with The New Press, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Promotional Materials: Advertisements, Flyers, and Press Releases, 1991-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Promotional Materials: Interviews with/about Greg Ruggiero and Stuart Sahulka, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Reviews: Open Media Pamphlets, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Zapatistas: Spreading Hope for Grassroots Change Starting from Chiapas, Mexico (Pamphlet, 1994): Research File, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Cover art, Open Magazine Pamphlet Series, 1993 (Box Shared Tamiment 007, Folder 2)
- Photographs, graphics, undated (Box 3)